Vishvjitsinh(Vish) Ravalji

Front-End Web Developer

Montreal QC, Canada | vishvajitravalji@gmail.com | +1-514-918-7149 |



in Linkedin



Portfolio



Github

SUMMARY

Junior Web Developer with around 1 plus years of experience in the field of Web development. Experience in Design and Development of responsive websites and SaaS. Extensive knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and Bootstrap. Good in OOPs concept and basic knowledge of Back-end, AWS and Bigdata technologies.

SKILLS

Experience with: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, Bootstrap4, React, JSON

Knowledge of: PHP, Spring MVC, Java, Scala, WordPress, HDFS, Spark, Kafka, Tableau, Git/GitHub

Query engine and databases: MySQL, H2, Hive HUE, AWS Athena

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Intern

FANIQUE (Toronto, Canada) Upcoming: Sept 2021 – Dec 2021

Junior Web Developer

YOTTOL Tech (Anand, India)

Apr 2018 - Apr 2019

Key Deliverables:

- Developed the web based applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap and WordPress.
- Created and maintained mutual fund management platform that enabled our internal analytics team to increase reporting speed.
- Made changes to existing web pages according to the feedback received from the end users or
- In some cases, changes are also made in order to update the applications compatibility with the latest operating systems.
- Managed database in MySQL and H2.

EDUCATION

Post Graduation in Big Data Development

MCIT (Montreal, Canada) Aug 2020 - July 2021

Post Graduation in Full Stack JAVA Development

MCIT (Montreal, Canada) July 2019 – June 2020

Bachelors in Computer Science

GTU (Vadodara, India) Aug 2014 - July 2018

GPA: 3.7

CERTIFICATION

Udemy - React - The Complete Guide

Clever Programmer - Web Development Bootcamp 2021

Udemy - Building an E-Commerce Store Using Java Spring Framework

Udemy - The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp

PROJECTS (Portfolio)

Contact Manager @ ()

- Implemented a responsive web-app Contact Manager using React and JSON Server.
- transformed JSON data.
- Skill: HTML5, CSS3, React, JavaScript ES6, Router, Json-Server, Axios, API, Material-ui

User and Age Manager 🏨 🎧

- Implemented a responsive web-app User & Age Manager using React.
- Execute error modules.
- Skill: HTML5, CSS3, React, JavaScript ES6

Expense Tracker 🏨 🞧

- Implemented a responsive web Expense Tracker Web-App using React and JavaScript ES6.
- transformed JSON data.
- Skill: HTML5, CSS3, React, JavaScript ES6, JSON

Job filter tool SaaS 🏨 🞧

- Implemented a responsive web tool using JavaScript ES6.
- transformed JSON data.
- Skill: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON

Responsive Website with API 🌘 😱

- Implemented a Responsive Website using BootStrap4.
- Used Mapbox API.
- Skill: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, API

ETL pipeline of GBFS(BIXI) data @

- Implemented an automatic ETL pipeline for JSON data files of BIXI.
- Download and transformed JSON files to CSV and write them on the HDFS.
- Used Hive JDBC to execute a cross join between your two external tables and load data into the final table.
- Skill: Scala, Spark Streaming, Kafka, Zookeeper, SQL, Hive, HDFS, Hadoop, Parquet and Avro

Task Management System 🌘 🕠

- Build a full-stack web app to allow users to do CRUD operations.
- It's managed by Leader, Member and Admin.
- Skill: Java, Spring, MVC, Maven, JSP, H2 DB

Automated Wheel-Chair @

- Completed project on Automated wheel chair that allows handicapped person to operate from mobile device.
- Worked on microcontrollers such as Raspberry Pi and Arduino
- Skill: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and IoT